MAXWELL WENGER

SOFTWARE ENGINEER / NETWORK ENGINEER

CONTACT



425.780.3119



maxdwneger@gmail.com in /in/Maxwell-Wenger



www.maxwenger.com



github.com/maxwenger



Seattle, WA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

C# .NET / .NET Core WPF / ASP.NET MVC **Entity Framework** NancyFX

Stored Procedures / MSSQL

Git / Visual Studio TS

Agile / SDLC methodology

Unit Testing

Docker / Docker Compose

Azure / AWS / Digital Ocean

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATION

Windows Server

Linux

ADDS / DNS / DHCP / RRAS

Cloudflare

Virtualization / ESXi

IIS / Apache / NGINX

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

In my career, I will develop and maintain software and computer systems. My technological expertise allows me to be precise in my solutions, while my business acumen gives me the tools to be accurate in the implementation. I face every challenge with an unstoppable, enthusiastic, and competitive force that will not subside until I am satisfied with a solution.

EXPERIENCE

OWNFR

Eastside Consulting | Woodinville, WA | April 2017 - Present

Subcontracted under a larger prime contractor to consult IT solutions.

- Recovered a military contractor from a foreign ransomware attack.
- Implemented backup solutions for safety-critical, mission-critical, and business-critical data.
- Restored and updated ERP systems from a catastrophic state.
- Deployed and maintained IT and application systems including Active Directory, Hyper-V, MSSQL, DNS, DHCP, RRAS, and IIS.
- Facilitated internet provider transitions.
- Most projects included heavy documentation and working with internal
- Experience working in secure datacenters in the Seattle and Lynnwood

MOBILE TECHNOLOGY CREW

Bellevue School District | Bellevue, WA | Summer of 2017

Traveled to onsite locations to prepare technology for the following school year.

- Installed network and IT equipment during the construction of an elementary school.
- Maintained and repaired student and staff laptops using PXE, MDT and SCCM.

PROGRAM COMMITTEES

PRESIDENT

Newport Cisco Project Club and Bellevue Breakfast Rotary Club | 2017 – 2018

- Donates equipment and student labor to build computer labs for schools in developing countries in affiliation with the BBRC and rotary clubs local to the project.
- Raised over \$2,500 for student scholarships.

NETWORKING

Cisco IOS / Cisco ASA

Multiarea OSPF

TACACS AAA

iBGP / eBGP

VoIP (SCCP / Cisco UCM)

VPN Technologies

VRF

MPLS

Policy-Based Routing

VLANs

CERTIFICATION

MTA: Software
Development
Fundamentals *Microsoft*April 2, 2016

EDUCATION

CCNA & CCNP Training

NHS Cisco Networking Academy 2016 – 2018

Cascadia College 2017 - Present

Woodinville High School Class of 2018

HONORS / AWARDS

9TH PLACE INTERNATIONALLY IN NETWORKING CONCEPTS FBLA (Future Business Leaders of America) | Anaheim, CA | 2017

1ST PLACE DESTKTOP APPLICATIONS DEVELOPMENT FBLA (Future Business Leaders of America) | Bothell, WA | 2016

1TH PLACE MANAGEMENT DECISION MAKING FBLA (Future Business Leaders of America) | Edmonds, WA | 2015

#HACKHARASSMENT AWARD

DefHacks(), Intel | Microsoft, Redmond Campus | 2017

 Developed an application that used a neural network and speech recognition software (TTS & STT) to prevent online harassment and bullying.

PROJECTS

EVE-NG

EVE-NG, Dynamips, ESXi, Linux, Cisco Viral | December 2017

- Virtualized a Cisco lab with real Cisco IOS images, replacing the need for expensive lab equipment, making Cisco training more accessible.
- Saves at least \$500.00 per Cisco certification candidate on lab equipment.

MicroCount

C# .NET Core, Redis, Docker, Docker Compose, Nginx, NancyFX | October 2017

- Completed as a demonstration for microservices.
- Runs three services behind a Nginx reverse proxy that follow the microservice pattern.
- Counts website "hits" with one service, writes them to a Redis database in another service, and reads the hits to a website in the third service.

PriceNotifier

C# .NET | March 2017

- Aids online sellers by ensuring the user has the lowest sell price to get the preferred spot on Google Shopping.
- Inputs a list of UPCs and prices to monitor and notifies the user when another listed item goes below the user's sell price.

QuickConfig

C# .NET | February 2017

- Configuration template manager for Cisco devices.
- Saves templates for a set of configurations and inputs new values to reduce redundant configurations between devices.

Personal Interests

- Aviation Pursuing a Private Pilot License (PPL).
- Guitar Instrumental, folk, and rock.
- Maritime SCUBA (PADI Open Water), Fishing, Boating